Eliott Davidson

Seattle WA | 206-437-8634 | eliott.davidson@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/eliott-davidson www.github.com/fussypuppet davidson.dev

Summary

I am a software engineer with a background ranging from social work to biology research. Whether it is answering unknowns about cellular function, translating confusing documents into approachable language, or designing code, I'm driven by a desire to distill complicated problems down to their core issues and deliver value, clarity, & efficiency.

Technical Skills

Languages: JavaScript, Dart, Python, TypeScript, HTML, CSS **Frameworks:** React, Flutter, Node.js, Express.js, NextJS

Databases: MongoDB, PostgreSQL **Other:** Git, GitHub, MS Office, Illustrator

United States Deetal Services City Corrier Assistant

Software Development Experience

Full-stack web development trainee General Assembly Seattle, WA Completed immersive web development training program involving over 500 hours of experience creating full-stack applications using JavaScript & Python and mobile applications using Dart.

Professional Experience

Margar Island MA 2017 present

United States Postal Service	City Carrier Assistant	wercer Island, wa	2017-present	
Kaplan Test Prep	Instructor / Course Administrator	Seattle, WA	2015-2016	
Taught classes on standardized test-taking skills for the GMAT exam.				
University of Washington	Post-Doctoral Fellow	Seattle, WA	2014	
University of Washington	Graduate Student	Seattle, WA	2006-2013	
Investigated the mechanics of cell division using a variety of biochemical and genetic techniques				
TURN Community Services	Instructor	Salt Lake City, UT	2003-2005	

Taught basic life skills to and advocated for adults with developmental disabilities

Education

Software Engineering Immersive Program	General Assembly	Seattle, WA
PhD, Molecular & Cellular Biology	University of Washington	Seattle, WA
BA, Biology	University of Utah	Salt Lake City, UT